Hey guys, Pastor Myers here and um I'm
going to be taking uh some time to
create some short videos on how to use
the photo theology GPT.
Now, there are so many different
features to this that it's going to take
me a bunch of videos to actually do this
and show you everything this thing can
do. Um so, these are going to be short,
you know, 5 to 10 minute videos. And
today I'm going to show you the photo
theology commentary. Yes, you heard that
right, the photo theology commentary. So
I'm going to go ahead and share my
screen. I'm going to be up in the
corner. Uh you're not going to, you
know, see we're going to focus on the
GPT and I want you to check this out,
guys. So let me share my screen.
Um and you will see here the photoology
app. So, it's photoology
GPT. All right. And uh let me go ahead.
I'm going to go ahead and click uh on
that first photoology right there. Uh
and it's going to take me into the GPT.
And I'm just going to go ahead and type
in hello.
And uh what it's going to do is it's
going to respond and give me several
options, right? And the option that
we're looking for is the commentary
mode. So, as you can see, I'm not going
to read all of this, but would you like
what would you like to do today? Choose
a mode like commentary. And that's what
I'm going to choose. I'm going to choose
the commentary
commentary mode. Right?
So,
what it's going to do is it's going to
give me three options.
Option one is the palace mode.
Option two is the room mode. And option
three is the principal mode. So, we're
just going to deal with the palace mode
first. Okay? And what the palace mode
is, palace mode does is it'll take one
verse, whatever verse you give it that
you want to uh you want a commentary on,
and it's going to run that verse through
every room of the photo theology palace.
every room. There are 38 rooms in a
photo theology palace. One room I'm
about to add, there's 37 that you see
right now, but I just want to give you
an example. So, let me type in palace
mode.
And um and then it's going to ask me uh
what verse I want to commentary on.
So, let's let it load.
And um here you're going to see it's
going to ask me what level and what
language. So I've chosen pro mode. You
can put in if you use this, it'll give
you an option between basic mode,
intermediate, advanced, and pro. So I'm
putting in pro. And um now it's going to
ask me for a verse. So what I'm going to
do is I'm going to give it Genesis
chapter 3:15.
And what this is going to do
is it's going to funnel Genesis 3:15
through every room of the palace.
And then it's going to come back and
give me a response, a commentary on this
one verse
through every room of the palace. It's
going to kind of go through and then
bring it all together. So this is all
one verse, guys. Now, I'm not going to
read this whole thing, but let me just
give you the synthesis. So, you can see
that it's taking you through. It's
showing you several of the rooms. It's
going through all the rooms. Okay? It's
going to go through all the rooms, but
uh I'm just going to give you the
synthesis, the synthesis. And it says
here, Genesis 3:15 stands as the Bible's
foundational gospel declaration,
igniting the great controversy with a
promise of divine intervention that
threads through every room of the
palace, revealing Christ as the ultimate
seed who resolves humanity's fall. In
the observation room, we see the raw
structure. God's word to the serpent
pivot. The God's words to the servant
pivot from immediate curse to forward
hope, imposing enmity not as mere
strife, but as a protective barrier
against total surrender to evil. This
lexical depth in the def the this
lexical depth in the def room clarified
seed as the multifaceted literal in
Christ's virgin's birth from Eve's line
collective in the church as Abraham's
spiritual heirs echoing Paul's use in
Romans and Galatians to affirm believers
inclusion through faith and it goes on
this is all commentary on one verse okay
So
I'm going to scroll down now and I'm
going to I'm going to ask to change the
mode. So now what I'm going to say is
I'm going to say let's let's
change to and by the way you can see
that there are options here right um you
can actually ask hey take this one
sentence or this one paragraph and
expand on this thought or take this one
room and expand on this room but I'm
going to say let's change to room mode.
So now we've moved from palace mode
where it takes the text through every uh
room in the palace and now we're going
to room mode. And in room mode, it's
going to ask me what room do I want to
go through first. In other words, let's
analyze this verse again, but I now want
to take it through, let's say, the theme
room. So, in the theme room,
um the theme room is it's set up as uh
the heaven ceiling, the gospel floor,
the life of Christ wall, the great
controversy wall, the time prophecy
wall, and the um the
uh sanctuary wall. So, I think I got all
those four. sanctuary, life of Christ,
great controversy, and time prophecy
wall. And what it's going to do is it's
going to look at that text within the
context of all of those themes. So, I'm
going to go ahead and push theme room
and let's see what it does.
All right. So now you can see it is now
commenting on this verse against the
backdrop of all of these themes. So for
example, let's just take the time
prophecy wall. This seed promise
initiates timelines like the 2300 days
from Eden to 1844 in 1844's
investigative judgment where enmity
culminates in judgment on all evil
powers. So wow. Never thought about
connecting Genesis Genesis 3:15 with the
2300 day prophecy before. Man, that
might be a whole Bible study. That might
be a whole sermon, right? There's a
sanctuary wall. Enmity ties to
atonement's blueprint. Christ as a true
sacrifice, bearing sin's penalty, while
the scapegoat, Satan, bears final
accountability, resolving the
controversy in heaven's cleansing. Hm.
Never thought to connect Genesis 3:15
with the Day of Atonement with the
scapegoat and the Lord's goal. Wow.
Never thought about that. Well, let me
let me do a study on that. So, again,
you can see that's just one room. After
we're done with that room, we can say,
"All right, let's go another room. Let's
go to uh let's go to the dimensions
room." Now, remember, in the dimensions
room, there are five dimensions, right?
There's a literal dimension, there's the
Christ dimension, there's the me
dimension, there's the church dimension,
and then there's the heaven dimension.
Let's have this commentary
uh this verse
go through the the dimensions room and
let's see what it gives us. And now you
can see it is giving us Genesis 3:15 in
five different dimensions.
Five different dimensions. And let's
just look at dimension five. Ultimately,
enmity enmity resolves in the third
heaven's new creation where Satan's
defeat is final. Revelation 20:10. And
the faithful seed dwell eternally with
God. Revelation 21:3 and 4. It reveals
God's character. Love that implants o
love that implants opposition to evil.
Transcending time into reflexive mastery
of truth. Okay. So that's the five
dimensions. Now we can go to another
room and you get the idea. You can go
room by room
through 38 different rooms saying, "Give
me commentary on this. Expound on it. Go
deeper." Now, I'm gonna I'm gonna switch
one more time. I'm going to switch to
principal mode. Principal mode.
So, what is the principal mode?
in the principal mode what you can now
do
watch this
so remember in each room right like we
said there's in the five dimensions room
in the dimensions room there's five
dimensions so each one of those
dimensions represents a principle you
can say hey photo theology GPT I want
you to give me commentary on this verse
using let's say the fourth dimension
Let's say uh the no let's say the noic
cycle.
Let's say the great no no let's say the
sanctuary wall.
Um let's add in there
um
the 400year prophecy.
Children of Israel in captivity for 400
years. So, I'm using a symbol here,
you'll know, and I'll explain that
symbol another time. Each one of these
principles has a symbol connected to it.
So, that one of the things you can do,
in fact, the equation mode, and I'll
talk about that another time. Um, I'll
make another video on that. The equation
mode is where you're actually looking at
the Bible through what looks like
mathematical equations. And the GPT will
give you an equation. Here's a story.
And apply these symbols to that story.
It's an equation, a problem that you get
to work out. I'll talk about that
another time. Okay, so we're going at uh
the the 400year prophecy of the children
of Israel in Egyptian captivity. And
let's add one more. Let's go um
let's say
let's say in fact I'm not going to use
this. I'm going to say uh the feast
of
tabernacles.
That's one of the principles. Uh the
feast room. How do I look at this verse
in light of all seven feasts? Or how do
I look at this verse in light of one
particular feast? So, we're going to
choose a feast of t feast of
tabernacles. Let's hit enter and let's
see what it does.
All right. So, here we go.
So, now what it does, it takes Genesis
3:15 and it's now applying fourth
dimension, meaning how does it relate to
the church? The noeic cycle, meaning uh
what from the story of Noah or the the
the gospel cycle of Noah. I don't have
time to get into that right now. It's
part of the fourth theology principle.
There are eight cycles. There's the
Adamic cycle. There's a noic cycle.
There's the um the the mosaic cycle. So,
this is a noic cycle. It's going to take
something from the noic cycle. It's
going to use the sanctuary room. It's
going to and I could have actually said
in the sanctuary room um use the altar
of sacrifice specifically or the uh
seven branch candlesticks specifically,
but I didn't do that. I'm just giving
you an idea of how this works. Take the
400year prophecy and the feast of
tabernacles. And here's what it says.
Applying these specified principles to
Genesis 3:15 reveals the verse as a
prophetic seed planted in Eden soil
unfolding across time, sanctuary
patterns, and redemptive cycles
ultimately dwelling with God. The fourth
dimension principle as a prophetic
timeline layer in the dimensions room
frames enmity as a historic arc. God
imposes or God's imposed opposition
traces cannonwide through the woman's
seed from immediate postfall conflict
to the church's endurance and
persecution. Daniel 7:25 culminating in
the judgment that crushes Satan's head.
Revelation 20:10. Now remember the
fourth dimension is going to be how does
this relate to the church particularly
at the end of time. And that's what you
just saw there, right? And we can read
on. is going to talk about the noic
cycle. The noeic cycle from the cycles
room extends this enmity in uh enmity
extends this enmity initiates the adamic
fall ripples into Noah's era where
violence fills the earth. Revelation 6
vers I'm sorry Genesis 6 verse 5-11 as
the serpent seed multiplies evil. So now
what it's just done is taken Genesis
3:15 and applied it to the Noic cycle
highlighting that
the whole world seemed to become Satan's
seed at this time with the exception of
Noah,
right? And his family.
So you can see here that the the the
variations of this commentary are
endless. They're endless.
I'm going to go back to the palace room.
I'm going to show you one more thing.
Let's go back to the palace mode, but
this time choose a different path. So
now what it's going to do is it's going
to go back through the palace mode
again, all 38 rooms, but this time it's
going to choose a different path. In
other words, the first time it went
through the palace and it may have
chosen the 1260year prophecy out of the
time zone, out of the time prophecies
room, right? Out of the time prophecy
wall, it may have chosen
um the noic cycle out of all eight
cycles.
So in every room that it goes into, it
has the option of choosing one of the
principles in that room. So now it's
going to go back and it's going to
choose
diff a different path meaning different
principles
within the same room
to produce a totally new commentary.
So you guys when I say that this
commentary is dynamic
I mean it is dynamic. Let me show you
again. I'm just going to scroll all the
way up you guys. And here's what I want
you to see.
All of this
starting from starting from
right here. Right here. All of this
All of this
is commentary
on one verse.
All right, y'all.
Photo theology.
photo theology gpt.com.
Check it out.
Peace you guys.